Hello friends, welcome to Tippon Sites.
In today's video, we are going to talk about the
claim of Care Health Insurance. In that, we have to take a reimbursement
claim. If
we get our treatment done in a non-network hospital, then the
process of it is resources. In that,
we have to fill claim forms
A and B. I am going to tell about it
in full detail. Today, what I am going to
tell you in this video is
about claim form A. So, please
watch the video till the end. If you are new to the channel, then
subscribe to the channel and
like the video. So let's start the video.
[Music]
First of all, it must be coming to your mind
that when we fill the reimbursement form, then
where will we get the form? The
TP team of some hospitals also provides it.
If you go there and ask for it at the
hospital where you get the treatment done, then
they also provide it. If they do
not do it, then after that we
[Music] have to go to the
last of Care Health Insurance. We will get
a download option at the very bottom, we have to
go there.  It is there and you will find it below. Right now,
most of those things are available on the company's website.
If you look carefully, you
will find it. You will see that this download option has come
here. After the download option, look
here,
this download option has come below it.
Look, it says claim procedure.
Claim form is written below it. So, if we
want a claim form, what we have to do is
click on claim form. If we
click on claim form here, the claim
form will open here.
Look,
we do not need the cashless form because
if we had got the cashless form, we would have gone to a network
hospital. Then the
TP team there
gives us the cashless form. That form is for their need.
But if we have not got the cashless form, then
we can download the
resource claim form in English or Hindi as well.
So, what is there in it,
we will download this English form.
Click on the PDF here.
I have downloaded it here. So,
we will open it from here.
Before filling this form, I am going to tell you a
couple of things first. What is there in it,
whenever we go to a non-network hospital  When we get admitted
in a hospital for treatment,
we have to call the insurance company and
inform them that we are getting
our treatment done in this hospital. If it is a
non-network hospital, then they provide
us with a claim number called an intimation number.
We have to
fill it in the reimbursement form A and B as well. There is
a particular claim number.
Our case starts with that claim number and
continues with that number till the time it is not settled. So
now see, the claim form of Care Health Insurance has opened in front of you. Now
look at this.
In today's video, you are talking about Part A.
So look at Part A, it is
written here. In Part A, in the first place, it is written '
To be fed by the insured'. This
form has to be filled by the insured, meaning the policy holder,
his details will be entered in it
and in the last place, it is written 'To be fed
in block letters'. This will be filled in block letters.
The issue form is not admission. This
means that this issue form is
not giving admission i.e. liability.
Something is written in type, their terms are written
inside it, after this the first option we get
is claim intimation number which I was
just telling you guys that
whenever we get admitted in a non-network hospital,
we have to give information to the company
that our relative or
our patient is admitted in this hospital,
you give us an intimation number
so that we can mention it in the form when we put it in the rebus, so
they give a number,
that number has to be mentioned here,
after that comes the policy number,
after that the policy number, here the
policy number is written on the details of your policy, along with the
policy number there is a
certificate number, you
can enter that too if you want, otherwise the policy number will
also work, then what happens with Care
Health Insurance, for example, suppose there is
a family policy, it is a family policy, then
what is there in it that everyone has a separate TP
ID number, if there are four candidates then all
four will have separate numbers and
enter here, the TP ID number which has to be filled here
Its name has to be entered here, the
name of the main member will come here, who is the
main member in the policy, his name comes here
in plus, what will happen after that, the
address will come here,
further the address will be filled here, the state will be filled, the
city will be filled, okay, phone numbers will
come, their pin code will come, email ID, okay,
after this we move ahead, section B comes
and it is saying currently covered by any other
mediclaim oblique health
insurance, it is saying that apart from this mediclaim
or apart from health insurance, do you have any
separate health insurance, if
you do not have it then tick no on it,
if yes then you will have to mention the people below,
after that all these things will
automatically become no, after that we come to the
next option
section C details of insured person
hospitalized, it is asking to
enter the details in it, the name and complete details of the person who has been hospitalized,
whose treatment has taken place inside the hospital,
so
in the title you have to write whether he is Mr or Mrs, if he is Miss then
tick on Miss Mr, if he is
Mrs or Miss then
tick here  After that, whatever is the name of that patient, it has to be
mentioned here, whether it is male or
female, okay, what is his age,
it has to be mentioned here, his
date of birth has to be mentioned here,
after that the relationship with the primary insured, the
details that we have entered
here, see the details of primary insured, it is written in the details that we have entered here,
it is
written primary insured,
see here the details of primary insured,
what is the relation of this patient with the primary insured, we have to mention here, if it is
self, then self means himself,
self spouse means wife, then
tick on his wife, if there is a child, then if there is a father
or mother of the child, then tick it
or if there is someone else, then mention it here,
then what does this patient do, whether he is a
service person, self-employed, home
maker, retired student, it has to be mentioned,
his address will come below here,
we have to mention the address here, after that
mention the city, state and pin code and
phone here  We have to enter the number and email ID,
after that we come to section
D,
what is there in section D that is details of
hospitalization, in this they will
ask for details of hospitalization, so in this we have to fill the name
of the hospital where admitted, in which
hospital you have been admitted, here
you have to enter the name of the hospital,
after that room category occupied means
in which room did you people get the treatment, was it
day care, single, private room, semi
private, or sharing, all this has to be
seen here and whatever you have used in it, then
tick that, after that we come
next hospitalization due to, see due
to injury, illness, or maternity, if there is any injury, any accident, then
tick here, if there is any fever or malaria,
dengue or any other problem, then tick
here in illness and if it is
related to pregnancy or maternity, then tick here, so
these things have to be filled very carefully,
tick very carefully, after that here
date of injury, date of disease first
detected  Date of delivery, its
date has to be entered here, here the date will be entered here,
date of admission, date of admission and date of discharge, the
time of date of admission and the time of date
of discharge matters a lot,
you have to fill it very carefully in the reimbursement form,
all those things should match with each other, the
admission time or date on your discharge summary and the things that
you are filling in the claim form should be the same, there should
not be any difference in them,
date of admission has to be entered here,
date of admission has to be entered here, time of
admission, time of admission, when were you admitted, whenever
we get admitted in a hospital,
a
time is generated in their software, a date is generated, the same
we have to
mention in our reimbursement claim from the beginning till the end,
date of discharge, the date on which you were
discharged has to be
entered and here the time of
discharge has to be entered,
after that comes self-naked,
traffic accident, if any of these has happened then
you have to tick  Other wise you have to leave it,
after that if you tick something then you have to tick
ya medical legal ya yes or no, if a
report has been made to the police then this has to be mentioned, if an
MLC has been made then FIR has to be lodged then
this has to be mentioned, okay after that comes
section E claim of detail, what happens in it,
in the rebusment form it is
very compulsory to fill this detail in rebusment form A, in this you have to enter the
complete breakup of the bill,
what have you
spent, so in this it is
coming for pre hospitalization, first of all it will
not be for pre hospitalization, it will not be for
pre hospitalization, in this it will not be for pre hospitalization, in this the
amount of second hospitalization expense has to be entered here, you
people will
not be for pre hospitalization
and in this the hospitalization
expense, you people have to
mention the amount here, okay, any other
post means any expense incurred even after admission, it has to be
mentioned in it,
after that the total amount has to be entered here, after
writing the total
all the bills have to be attached here  You can also write it by doing this, you
can mention it anywhere in it, after that comes
D option, D option is very important,
in this you are filling the claim form for
remembrance, so what supporting
documents are you attaching in it, those things matter a lot, firstly it is
very compulsory to attach the claim form,
one claim intimation intimation which
I told in the beginning, main
bill of the hospital, breakup of the bill, hospital payment
receipt, hospital discharge summary, this is very
important, pharmacy bill means if
any operation of medicine has been done then operation
notes, if ECG has been done then ECG, doctor
request for investigation,
investigation means whatever tests etc. have been done,
lab tests have to be
entered here, doctor prescription means
OPD has to be mentioned here at last, if there is
any other document separately then you have to
mention it here, in
this comes section F detail of bills n
close, see here, you have to enter the details of the bill,
you have to enter the bill number, date has to be
entered, what is the amount of the main bill issued by the hospital
What was the pre-hospitalization amount? Whatever post you are submitting, you will
mention that here. At the
end, you will write the total here.
What comes after that, in section G,
details of primary insured bank
account. They are saying that
we need the bank details of the primary insured.
What happens in case of reimbursement is that
when we send all our documents to the insurance
company, then the insurance
company deposits the money in our account. If it deposits the money
in our account, then
in which account will it deposit the money? They
need those details, so in the details asked for it,
this PAN card is asked here. Next, you have to
enter the PAN card here.
Account number has to be entered here. The name of the bank has to be entered
here. If it is a cheque, then the cheque details have to be
written in it. If it is a DD, then DD has to be entered.
IFSC code is an IFSC code of the bank,
every bank has a different one, that has to be
mentioned here. After that, your entire
form is completed. Here you have to
enter the date on which you are
filling the form or the date on which you are
submitting it.  You have to
enter your place, whichever district or
state you belong to, you have to
mention it here and the signature of the insured will be
signed here by the insured person, so this is the
claim form A of Care Health Insurance
Company which I have told you in detail, you have to
fill it very carefully, if you make
any mistake in it, if you fill any detail incomplete, then
queries will be made, additional
documents will be asked for, the more
queries there will be, the more
time it will take to settle the claim, so each and every
thing has to be filled very meticulously, if you do not understand then
go to the hospital where you have got the treatment done, there is
a team of TPA, you can take help from them,
they will help you completely, so in today's
video I told you people how to fill the
reimbursement form or
claim form A of Care Health Insurance, what is
its process, when we get
our treatment done in a non-network hospital,
in that condition we have to reimburse our bills
and
send them to the insurance company, so its
form which is filled is A and  B So
in today's video I told you about A,
in the next video I will
tell you about claim form B, so wait for that video to
come, if you liked this video then
like it and subscribe to the channel, we will
meet
in the next video, till then
hello.